export const chapter = "Chapter - 10: Sound";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "What are the three factors needed for communication through sound?",
          optionA: "Source, medium, and sensor",
          optionB: "Source, vibration, and frequency",
          optionC: "Medium, vibration, and hearing",
          correctAnswer: "A",
        },
        {
          question: "What happens when an object vibrates mechanically?",
          optionA: "It produces light",
          optionB: "It produces heat",
          optionC: "It produces sound",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the primary organ responsible for hearing in humans?",
          optionA: "Eyes",
          optionB: "Nose",
          optionC: "Ears",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the role of the eardrum in the process of hearing?",
          optionA: "It amplifies vibrations",
          optionB: "It transforms vibrations into nerve impulses",
          optionC: "It separates the outer ear from the middle ear",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the SI unit of frequency?",
          optionA: "Watt",
          optionB: "Hertz",
          optionC: "Decibel",
          correctAnswer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What characteristic of sound is related to the amplitude of vibrations?",
          optionA: "Loudness",
          optionB: "Pitch",
          optionC: "Quality",
          correctAnswer: "A",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the frequency range of sounds that the human ear can detect?",
          optionA: "1 Hz to 100 Hz",
          optionB: "10 Hz to 1,000 Hz",
          optionC: "20 Hz to 20,000 Hz",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the term for sound with a frequency above the audible range of hearing?",
          optionA: "Audible sound",
          optionB: "Infrasound",
          optionC: "Ultrasound",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question: "How is quality or timbre of a musical sound defined?",
          optionA: "It is related to the amplitude of vibrations",
          optionB: "It is the degree of sensation produced in the ear",
          optionC: "It enables the recognition of different sources of sound",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the measurement unit for noise?",
          optionA: "Watt",
          optionB: "Hertz",
          optionC: "Decibel",
          correctAnswer: "C",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "After independence, India's urban spaces continue to show colonial influence even today due to the ________ changes in political, social, economic, and cultural aspects of life.",
          optionA: "rapid",
          optionB: "enduring",
          optionC: "sporadic",
          correctAnswer: "enduring",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The process of urbanization occurs when a town comes into being and prominence due to various causes. For example, Calcutta and Bombay came into prominence when the British chose them as their centers of trade and then as ________ towns.",
          optionA: "presidency",
          optionB: "rural",
          optionC: "industrial",
          correctAnswer: "presidency",
        },
        {
          question:
            "De-urbanization can occur due to reasons like natural calamities, religious importance, tourism, and ________.",
          optionA: "agricultural growth",
          optionB: "political instability",
          optionC: "commercial decline",
          correctAnswer: "commercial decline",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Surat came to prominence when the East India Company established its factory there in 1612. However, after Bombay fell into its possession, Surat lost its importance. Presently, it has once again become a bustling town, especially due to trade in ________ and cotton.",
          optionA: "silk",
          optionB: "spices",
          optionC: "diamond",
          correctAnswer: "diamond",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Masulipatnam was set up with a factory in 1611 during the British period, but when this factory was shifted to Madras, this town lost its importance, primarily due to changes in ________.",
          optionA: "governance",
          optionB: "economic activities",
          optionC: "climate",
          correctAnswer: "economic activities",
        },
        {
          question:
            "During the colonial period, some Indian entrepreneurs started new industries at places which later developed into important industrial towns, such as ________.",
          optionA: "Jaipur",
          optionB: "Jamshedpur",
          optionC: "Jodhpur",
          correctAnswer: "Jamshedpur",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Hill Stations were established during the colonial period as the British sought cool places to give them respite from the extreme hot climate of India, and places like Darjeeling, Shimla, and Mussoorie were created as summer ________.",
          optionA: "retreats",
          optionB: "resorts",
          optionC: "sanctuaries",
          correctAnswer: "resorts",
        },
        {
          question:
            "A large number of pilgrimage towns have been in existence since earliest times, but with the introduction of railways, many of them became accessible, such as Haridwar, Ayodhya, Varanasi, Ujjain, and ________.",
          optionA: "Mathura",
          optionB: "Hampi",
          optionC: "Mahabalipuram",
          correctAnswer: "Mahabalipuram",
        },
        {
          question:
            "If we look around, we can find that one town often serves more than one purpose; for example, Bhopal serves as the capital town, trade town, tourist town, industrial townâ€”all at the same time. There are numerous other such ________.",
          optionA: "metropolises",
          optionB: "multipurpose towns",
          optionC: "business centers",
          correctAnswer: "multipurpose towns",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The British found the native system of town administration very haphazard, so they decided to reform the civic administration by introducing local self-government in municipalities. Lord Ripon favored this change, and he introduced a system where the government would have ultimate control and supervision of all municipalities while the actual administration would rest with the elected representatives of the people. This marked the introduction of local self-government in ________.",
          optionA: "villages",
          optionB: "towns",
          optionC: "colonies",
          correctAnswer: "towns",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "After independence, India's urban spaces no longer show colonial influence.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Urbanization occurs when a town comes into being and prominence due to various causes.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question: "De-urbanization only occurs due to political reasons.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Surat regained its importance primarily due to the trade in silk.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Hill Stations were established during the colonial period as a response to extreme cold climates in India.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Local self-government in municipalities was introduced by Lord Ripon.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Municipalities in towns are primarily funded by the central government.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Public Works Department (PWD) is responsible for the operation of various facilities like schools and parks.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "The first railway line was laid down in India in 1902.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The police organization in colonial India was known for its popularity and integrity among the common people.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
